William N. Fanton Sermons
William N. Fanton Sermons
1898-1917
Fanton, William N.
0.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American Methodist clergyman. Consists of Fanton's sermons and their source material, usually newspaper clippings, annotated with dates and places of delivery, all in New York State.
148970
Biographical History
William N. Fanton was an American Methodist clergyman.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William N. Fanton Sermons consist of sermons and the material (usually newspaper clippings) which inspired Fanton to write these particular sermons.
Arrangement of the Collection
Sermons are arranged chronologically. Clippings are filed with the sermon which they inspired.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Fanton, William N.; Clergy -- United States.; Methodist Church -- Clergy.; Methodist Church -- New York (State); Sermons, American.; Sermons.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Sermons
  - "Christ, the Universal Conqueror", first preached (f.p.) Oct 29, 1898 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Burden Bearing", f.p. Dec 18 1898 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Mary and Martha", f.p. Feb 19 1899 (Box 1)
  - "Simon's Money Fish", f.p. Aug 13 1899 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Art Thou in Health?", f.p. Aug 20 1899 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Life of Job", f.p. Dec 17 1899 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Triumphal Entry", f.p. Mar 31 1901 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Rational Enthusiasm", f.p. May 12 1901 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Tragedy of John the Baptist", f.p. Jul 21 1901 (Box 1)
  - "Promptness", f.p. Aug 18 1901 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Second Coming of Christ", f.p. Dec 29 1901 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Hebrew Poetry", f.p. Oct 21 1902 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Solomon", f.p. Jan 29 1905 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "The Religion of Lincoln", f.p. Feb 12 1905 (Box 1)
  - "The Rich Food, Covetousness", f.p. Sep 17 1905 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Unjust Steward", f.p. Sep 24 1905 (Box 1)
  - "The Net Drawn", f.p. Oct 22 1905 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "The Harvest of the Earth is Ripe", f.p. Oct 14 1906 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "If Son Make You Free", f.p. Sep 4 1910 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "The Soul Parts for God as a Boat for Water", f.p. Feb 5 1911 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "They Brought him to Him", f.p. Sep 1 1911 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "The Lord is with You if You're with Him", f.p. Sep 10 1911 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "Biographies of Historical Characters", f.p. Oct 6 1911 (p.m.) (Box 1)
  - "The Prison Opened", Dec 17 1911 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "God's Power Over Soul", Dec 31 1913 (Box 1)
  - "Mary vs. Joseph", f.p. Sep 20 1914 (a.m.) (Box 1)
  - "New Jerusalem", Jan 17 1915 (Box 1)
  - "Some Eccentricities of a Few Evangelists of Yesterday" (George Whitefield), f.p. Jan 4 1916 (Box 1)
  - "Bodily Exercise", Jul 30 1916 (Box 1)
  - "Thanksgiving", Nov 29 1917 (Box 1)